<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Python</title>
      <link>/blog/intro-to-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/intro-to-python/</guid>
      <description>Python Basics Python was pretty challenging for me to learn at first, so here are some basics that should help other python learners!
One of the coolest parts about using Python in RStudio is combining the two together. This allows you to combine objects from both Python and R, which can let you write fun sentences.
library(reticulate) wow&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;python can be&amp;quot; surprise =&amp;quot;really fun&amp;quot; print(r.wow,surprise) ## (&amp;#39;python can be&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;really fun&amp;#39;) Another thing that is unique about Python (and kinda cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>0. Introduction For this assignment, I chose to use the dataset ‘Salaries’ from the ‘carData’ package. There are 397 observations on 6 variables: rank, discipline, yrs.since.phd, yrs.service, sex and salary. Rank represents title, as in Professor, Assistant Professor or Associate Professor. Discipline has two levels representing department type, A (theoretical) or B (applied). The variable “yrs.since.phd” represents the number of years the individual has had their PhD. The variable “yrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
For this project, I chose to use two datasets. The first dataset is my personal Netflix data including everything I have streamed from 2014 to present day, and the second dataset is Austin weather from 2013 to 2017. The Netflix dataset has only two variables, the TV show/movie title and the date it was streamed. I was able to download the data directly from the Netflix website while signed into my account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>